Home Address 7, Alahaji Odutan Sikiru Str, New Oko-Oba, Agege, Lagos, Nigeria.

Email: hello@faitholaniyi.com or faitholaniyi01@gmail.com

Phone: +2348103702624

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/faith

-olaniyi/

Olaniyi Faith Ayodeji

Summary

I am a creative generalist specialized in product and business management. He is an atypical thinker and problem solver who constantly generates innovative solutions to complex problems. He prides myself as a prolific technological management strategist, recognized for diverse experiences across varieties of industries.

As a tech and business savvy with over 4 years profound exposure in optimization, strategic planning, process communications, management & analytics; gained from across private, public, regional & international platforms. I bring my multi-skilled know-how to bear in boosting your product and business development portfolio.

An experienced Chief of Staff that works behind the scenes to make things easy for his principal. Member of the Chief of Staff Association in the US.

Work Experience

February 2021 Till present

SPAK AFRICA (spak.africa)

President and Founder

- Developed idea, built a team and facilitated the nonprofit technological product
- Drive growth, engagement, visibility, revenue generation and goal actualization.

December 2021 SPECIAL ADVISER TO ONDO STATE GOVT & CEO OF ONDO STATE

ENTREPRENEURSHIP AGENCY (https://ondea.ng/)

Till present Special assistant

Leverage on resourcefulness to provide solutions to

Faith Olaniyi Curriculum Vitae challenges

Email faitholaniyi01@gmail.com

- Facilitator in the entrepreneurship development training
- Develop training materials for entrepreneurs' development training
- Facilitate support in programs and event by the agency

October 2021 Till present

AFRICA'S YOUNG ENTREPRENEURS (<u>https://ayeorganization.com/</u>) Chief of Staff

- Manage the President's schedule, scheduling meeting, planning and executing needs with follow up
- Collaborate with executive teams to determine and prioritize business strategies and...
- Providing team members and leaders with recommendations and consultations to facilitate efficiency and productivity of their work with teamwork
- Planning, coordinating and keeping focused the goals, missions and visions of the organization
- Determining KPI for teams' performance
- Create systems for programs, activities and programs of the organization
- Product manager for the organization's products <u>http://entrepreneurshipvillage.com/</u> and <u>https://www.etrustfund.org/</u>

February 2018 Till present

CYCLEBREEZE INNOVATIONS (https://cyclebreeze.com/) Business, Product and Growth Lead

- Selected dexterous teams who were experts in their niche to facilitate in achieving of goals of the company.
- Initiated ideas to develop never before seen technological product and render services that are R&D focused that solves some of the world's challenges inclusive of SDG challenges.
- Currently leading a team which has secured horizontal business relationship with a new client in the first month.
- Investigate market activity and analyze published data and statistics through research.
- Create long-term value for an organization from customers, markets and relationships.
- Generate new leads for businesses.
- Growing the business, making it more competitive, expanding products or services, and/or focusing on specific markets.
- Ensure fulfilment of our philanthropic responsibilities by freely hosting an incubation event for competitors of the Hult Prize challenge, a \$1M UN challenge for SDG.
 Facilitated the development of the result checking

Faith Olaniyi Curriculum Vitae Email faitholaniyi01@gmail.com

- system for Ladoke Akintola University of Technology.
- Organized event where talents and individuals or group with products connect with employers, investors and techtycoons.
- Facilitated business planning and new product development for Cyclebreeze.
- Managed business and product developmental process for Cyclebreeze clients.
- Successfully built a tech ecosystem in their pilot location and launched a unique technological academy. academy.cyclebreeze.com

January 2021 Till present

AFRICA BLOCKCHAIN INSTITUTE (https://africablockchain.institute/)

Executive Assistant

Worked remotely with the MD in Rwanda based company on business, admin and operational requirements & physically managed their Made in Rwanda project.

- Developing business documents.
- Writing business proposals and pitching to investor with 100% positive revert.
- Hackathon event project manager and marketing strategist https://africablockchain.institute/campus-hackathon/

<u>Projects and Products I worked on or with while at ABI;</u>

- AgriDrone Tech (An IoT BASED BLOCKCHAIN AGRICULTURAL MONITORING AND CONTROL SYSTEM FOR SMART FARMING) with Mafor Ngwenyi – Cameroon.
- SmartX by Oliver of Kenya who created with Blockchain a FinTech product that solves the problems of financial transactions online as opposed table banking – Kenya.
- iMock, a digitalized educational app that provides quality assessment to school students and your professionals through a partial decentralised technology thereby making them achieve academy excellence. The product makes use of Blockchain technology for incentives and rewards and Artificial Intelligence AI to provide curation of the subjects with Joshua – Nigeria.

Faith Olaniyi Curriculum Vitae• Email faitholaniyi01@gmail.com

Ni-he A social ecommerce platform – Rwanda. I developed

and implemented product timelines and ensured featured prioritization as I worked with both the design and development team. I also facilitated preparations for their Made in Rwanda Pitch

- Digital Identity by San Tech Ltd of Shema and Claudine
 Nzime (System which is useful in facial recognition, finger
 print attendance, sccannng IDs and gps tracker in the same
 systems with camera for take picture of entrance vehicle in
 python desktop) (www.santechrwanda.com) Rwanda. I
 developed and implemented product timelines and
 ensured featured prioritization as I worked with both the
 design and development team. I also facilitated
 preparations for their Made in Rwanda Pitch.
- Spicy Rwanda. An Agric e-commerce company where I developed and implemented product timelines and ensured featured prioritization as I worked with both the design and development team. I also facilitated preparations for their Made in Rwanda Pitch.
- Smart Agriculture by Bright Future Contracting Company
 Ltd (www.brightfuture.co.rw) Mathieu BARIGITA and Eng.
 Jean Claude MANIRAFASHA Electrician at UNIVERSITY OF
 RWANDA; CEO of Bright Future Contracting Company Ltd;
 Founder of Africa Digital Internship Linkage; Founder of
 SMARTIRRIGATED AKARIMA Project Rwanda. I
 developed and implemented product timelines and
 ensured featured prioritization as I worked with both the
 design and development team. I also facilitated
 preparations for their Made in Rwanda Pitch.
- Hackathon event Africa. I was in charge of the planning, marketing and facilitated pitch deck preparations for all the competitors. Also, hosted the first day virtual event.
- Made in Rwanda Incubation program by Africa Blockchain Institute and MakerDAO https://africablockchain.institute/incubator-program/. I selected the technical team that would facilitate the products of all incubates and managed the development team. I also, created technical requirement, business cases with business plan and pitch decks that contained business models, ROI, marketing plan and go-to-market strategy. Also, part of the organizing team for the final day event in Rwanda.

2020 MetroBox (https://metrobox.com.ng/)

Business Developer

Developed the necessary structure and facilitated growth and development of the online procurement company. https://metrobox.com.ng/

- Created company structure and an operational model tailored to ensure seamless business activities
- Creatively generated blue ocean strategies against competitors to give distinctive buzz
- Led the tracking system development project

2019-2020 **cMapIT** (<u>https://cmapit.io/</u>)

Business/Product Consultant

Consulted on business, marketing and product needs of the renowned geographic information system software company https://cmapit.io/

- Business models facilitator
- Marketing, Business and Product Consultant

2017 SWITCH IDEA by STERLING BANK

Product Management Associate

I analyzed competition, conducted market research and suggested product enhancements to improve user experience.

Education

2014 – 2021 BSc Pure and Applied Mathematics

Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Oyo State, Nigeria.

2014 **SSCE**

From West Africa Examination Council. Institution attended, Honey Spring High School, Lagos state, Nigeria.

Other Activities

2016	Project manager for CADMAC
2016	Project management trainer RCCG Oyo state Province 5
2017	Official Pianist and model Konga Black Friday Ad aired on African
	magic, YouTube and other platforms.
2016	Pianist at Make Music Lagos
2019	Content writer and guest blogger at New Horizon, Blackhat Naija,
	Finance feat and other blog inclusive of freelancing on fiverr.
2019	WordPress Developer and Intern at Mentapps

2021	How to Build Digital Product at Product School
2021	How to Achieve Product-Market Fit at Product School
2021	Product Analytics Certification
2016	PMP Certificate of completion
2016	PMS Certificate of Completion
2018	Certificate of completion Google Digital Skill for Africa
2019	Google online Digital Marketing and Google my business

Training and Participations

2021	Maison Premiere Product class by Maison HQ
2021	Africa Young Leaders react to Blockchain with Anthony Day,
	Blockchain leader at IBM
2020	Hult Prize Competitor
2018	Google Hash Code
2016	Google online marketing challenge (GOMC) participant

Additional Skills

Teamwork and Leadership

 I work remotely in companies and have a good track record of completing task in all companies according to the milestone set.

Communication-Verbal and Written

- Speak English fluently with confidence
- I have pitched ideas, trained, spoke at events that polished my communication skills and built my confidence.

IT Skills

- Proficient in office 365
- Beginner graphic designer & slide builder
- WordPress developer
- Scrum Intermediate

Other Skills

- Analytical and logical thinker with a strong sense of judgment when it comes to Creative Content, products and Music pieces or performances
- Strong Background in Business, tech and music ecosystem, strategic and organizational planning. Enjoy stimulating, challenging and dynamic work environments.
- Highly Experienced in media content development and generation resulting in growth of audience base and increased profitability. Also, experienced in training, leading and organizing events. At ease and effective in

Faith Olaniyi Curriculum Vitae Email faitholaniyi01@gmail.com

- work situations requiring an ability to orchestrate multitask levels of responsibility effectively.
- Quick Learner with an ability to easily enter into new media frontiers, assess/interpret potential creative materials, capitalize on new or existing developments and plan/execute innovative and creative strategies.
 Dedicated and self-motivated team player.
- Problem solving, organizational and leadership skills.
 Resourceful in resolving emerging problems with great ability to work under pressure and meet deadlines.

Activities & Interests

I believe anything worth doing is worth doing well. Hence, I gear my energy towards excellence in everything I do. I play the piano and I love learning new things and especially, improving ideas. Creative thinking and complex problems solving.

Weakness:

- Love to always work hard without the consciousness of my body till breaking down or sickness warns me to take it slow.
- I find it difficult to work if I am not comfortable, but can make anything happen if I am comfortable.

References:

Will be sent upon request.